Speaker 0: It's Wednesday July 17th 2024.
Speaker 0: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We are reviewing the 2023 French animated neo-noir science fiction film Mars Express.
Speaker 1: Let's do this All right, so I went to a concert on Monday that I almost didn't go to oh the one you got the last-minute tickets to.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: So there's this person named IU who's basically like if you're in South Korea, she's actually probably the biggest Musical like the Taylor Swift them.
Speaker 1: South Korea like that the hugest deal, but outside of South Korea It's not like we're BTS.
Speaker 1: right where BTS is big in South Korea perhaps almost as big or as big as IU but Outside of South Korea BTS is also huge.
Speaker 1: yeah They're huge everywhere right IU?
Speaker 0: if you went to other countries Not it not so much like my measure there would be I think Thinking about conversations ahead of my co-workers almost everyone.
Speaker 0: I work with.
Speaker 0: many of these people are as old as me or older.
Speaker 0: They know who BTS are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean ever.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: everybody knows that BTS is yeah, they're huge.
Speaker 1: right so it's like.
Speaker 1: But anyway.
Speaker 1: so for the first time IU has been around so long.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: she started when she was way young And she's just been going ever since.
Speaker 1: right and But she has not had to my knowledge like a solo Us concert, I don't know if she was maybe saying it like what a kcon or something like that one time.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but first ever you had real us tour with arenas, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm like.
Speaker 1: I'm not like the biggest IU fan ever, but like she's good She didn't get there with no talent or anything right.
Speaker 1: you know she's legit.
Speaker 1: She actually sings unlike a lot of other people who just lip-sync everything and she does it all by herself.
Speaker 1: And she basically you know at some point in her career She started out like everyone else But then she became a big enough deal to sort of like.
Speaker 1: you know take her own career into her own hands.
Speaker 1: So she sort of does it the way she wants.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is that she's very Fan service II right.
Speaker 1: she like goes out of her way to do Right.
Speaker 1: it's like if she's like if you're my fan I'll make sure it's worth your while.
Speaker 1: the exact opposite of a geek night.
Speaker 0: I was about to say the exact opposite of one Scott Ruben right.
Speaker 1: It's like don't listen to my show.
Speaker 1: I use like if you come and Listen to me and my fan.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make you.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make sure Right to you know to make worth it for you.
Speaker 1: so anyway She has this show and I go to buy tickets.
Speaker 1: right when they first go on sale It's at the New Jersey Devils Prudential Center, which I actually hadn't been in before anyway, so it's not that hard to get to you.
Speaker 1: just path train over there and This you know.
Speaker 1: maybe close to 20,000 seats in there or something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't know the exact number.
Speaker 1: and when I get in the Ticketmaster queue There's like hundreds of thousands in the queue, and I'm like well.
Speaker 1: This isn't happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah sure enough It's sold out, but the next day I go and I look at resale tickets And there's a shit ton of resale tickets like a lot And it's like these sellers keep making the same damn mistake I think.
Speaker 1: and I'm like they all the resellers bought all the tickets to this show But there isn't enough demand like if that was a Taylor Swift show.
Speaker 1: Resellers yeah, what I got in some of the tickets, but the next day.
Speaker 1: They would have been all gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah Regardless of price here the resellers were trying to go for a high price, and they weren't moving.
Speaker 1: And so I'm like all right.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll just wait in a game of chicken with them until the last day Until I see what's up right and some people maybe if it's still too high I don't care that much.
Speaker 1: I won't go and if I can get a good price.
Speaker 1: Okay, maybe it'll be worth it.
Speaker 0: That's how I did that Janelle Monae concert and the two nights before I was like oh yeah that concert.
Speaker 0: And I looked and I saw those like third row seats for 80 bucks.
Speaker 1: I even I tried to research how late how long can you go in this game of chicken?
Speaker 1: because obviously you're betting against a Well other people buy all the tickets first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, then then your SOL.
Speaker 0: well I learned for NHL playoff games in MSG Five minutes before the game there are some cheap tickets sometimes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: or Will the ticket sellers just sit on their high price right like a landlord with a vacant store and say?
Speaker 1: Sorry thousand dollars or nothing right and then just eat the eat the cost.
Speaker 1: And it's like that that can happen to good happens.
Speaker 1: I wait.
Speaker 1: It's a powerful motivator.
Speaker 1: So I waited until the last day and the ticket prices were still like free $400 and I'm like nope that ain't worth it right.
Speaker 1: and then on the day of.
Speaker 1: I see one two seats and I'll luxury box and They're like 275 and I'm like.
Speaker 1: you know that's cheaper than some of the ones I've seen up in the nosebleeds, and it's also the cheapest tickets.
Speaker 1: I see on here and That's not too bad, and it'll be kind of comfy.
Speaker 0: I guess right That would be worth the experience.
Speaker 1: I would be worried about people with like cameras in front of you right and So I bought the luxury box tickets and we went and it was.
Speaker 1: you know I would have liked to pay a little bit less But actually I kept checking even though I already had tickets, and I wasn't gonna like I was gonna resell.
Speaker 1: But I kept checking just to see you know for next time for research purposes and Actually, I didn't see a single ticket lower than that the whole time up until the show and they did sell them all eventually.
Speaker 1: So I guess the scalpers won that one yeah, and I should have charged more money.
Speaker 1: But was interesting at the show is that I one thing that was really Interesting is that on IU with her fan service ways had gifts prepared for all the fans And they were like they're handing out free gifts when you went in mm-hmm and it was like a little metal tin that had key chains and pictures of IU a magnet.
Speaker 1: and When I went to go you know Get my ticket scan and get a free goodie, which I didn't care that much, but I'm like well free goodie Whatever right you could resell that an eBay probably.
Speaker 1: They were like no you got to go over there with your luxury box ticket And I'm like okay, and like can I get the free goodie?
Speaker 1: cuz I didn't see other the free Goodie wasn't being handed out over by the luxury box door, and they're like no Like I'm like all right Okay, I guess.
Speaker 1: and so I go to the luxury box And we see the show and I could.
Speaker 1: I wrote about it on the forum.
Speaker 1: you can read it there.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna waste the whole podcast talking about it But if IU is coming to your city It's gonna be cheaper than it was for me because I looked at the other city prices.
Speaker 1: They were a lot cheaper.
Speaker 1: I saw like Georgia 60 bucks right.
Speaker 1: so if she's coming near you you should go.
Speaker 1: But regardless the on the way out they made it P after the show was actually over After many hours like close to 11 Started it like before 8 so over 3 hours, right?
Speaker 1: They made an announcement.
Speaker 1: They're like hey if you didn't get the free goodie, and you had a standard ticket go see an usher Like only standard tickets, and I'm like huh, and I saw people online that were like yeah They only gave the free gift.
Speaker 1: They were really sticklers about it And they checked everyone's ticket to make sure it wasn't as a special ticket.
Speaker 1: But only the standard tickets could get the free goodie, and I'm like what happened here, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: you know did like This.
Speaker 0: is this a like?
Speaker 0: imagine if alcohol nerd convention Gave the special stuff to the regular attendees if you bought the $500 special gold package, and I didn't get that stuff.
Speaker 1: well I don't know how it were right.
Speaker 1: cuz like some of the luxury boxes were empty.
Speaker 1: cuz Clearly luxury box tickets.
Speaker 1: Don't just go on sale with the other tickets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So it's like.
Speaker 1: did I use not get money when the from the luxury box ticket sales to the people who reserve who own the luxury Boxes?
Speaker 1: do they write cuz clearly I bought it from the person who owns the luxury.
Speaker 0: Oh, do they just get tickets to anything that's in the arena.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: did they cut out the you know the concert people from Those sales as I don't know it works at MSG.
Speaker 0: I don't think if you have a luxury box for the rain.
Speaker 1: I don't know how a luxury box works.
Speaker 1: I've never I've sat in them, but I've never owned one.
Speaker 1: I've never managed the tickets for one.
Speaker 1: so how the hell it works.
Speaker 1: But I do know that like if you the one thing I do know is like you had to pay to get the luxury Box and then you do have to buy your tickets right to the seats that are in your luxury box.
Speaker 1: Yeah some people had standing room only tickets.
Speaker 1: in the luxury box that we were in.
Speaker 1: we had tickets specifically for two of the seats in the box.
Speaker 1: so and Also was funny as I added my ticket to the to the Apple Wallet.
Speaker 1: it was a New Jersey Devil's style ticket And I'm like it said I you it got me in.
Speaker 1: it was a legitimate ticket.
Speaker 1: I was in the luxury box, but Something was.
Speaker 1: something was going on there And it's like I'm surprised like all the arena staff like all of them.
Speaker 1: Not you know these low low paid people like really cared about following that rule like they were very strict that Something like what you described.
Speaker 0: there's definitely a shenanigans that was going on.
Speaker 1: there was some shenanigans that was happening with this And I'm just I can't.
Speaker 1: I can only guess at what it was.
Speaker 1: it was just that was really fascinating that that happened.
Speaker 1: But yeah feel free if you see a show you want to go to that has a lot of resale tickets available And they're not moving.
Speaker 1: wait to the last day or even the last hour if you can if you can get away with it.
Speaker 0: No in the future like if it there's a sale hockey playoff game that we don't have tickets from our half season four I Feel like I might just hang around outside MSG with my phone and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it's a place that if it's not a big travel.
Speaker 1: But I mean I saw people online saying that they would drive to cut to Concerts with no tickets in hand and buy them like in the car on the way with like 30 minutes to go.
Speaker 1: see I have Never been into something that much that deeply Me either, but people said that they do that and they get away with it, and they save money, and it's like oh, yeah All righty, then that's Congrats.
Speaker 0: You know real benefit, then if if you live in a place like New York City.
Speaker 0: It's a lot easier to do this because I could sit at home buy tickets to something and if I hit Just take the subway right to where I'm paying with my rent instead of with my.
Speaker 0: yeah So it's probably way more expensive in the end, but
Speaker 1: yeah There there is a show in early August I want to go to a Radio City that has even like a shit ton of the tickets are on resale like I'd say the More well over half of the the place, and I'm like huh?
Speaker 1: All right, I'll just wait to the last day.
Speaker 0: then I guess yeah That whole resale thing is a topic.
Speaker 0: That's in the regular media increasingly as I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like that whole Space is evolving rapidly, and I feel like resellers are Missing the mark and fucking up The read.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: but you know Ticketmaster is cleaning up because when you oh, yeah The reseller assumes all the risk.
Speaker 1: now right so you sell the takes ticket Ticketmaster Guarantees that all the tickets will be sold so they get the maximum amount of fees on those first sales.
Speaker 1: And then if any resales happen through Ticketmaster Alright, then they get a second dip on that ticket.
Speaker 1: ergo, and that's only ticket master can't like make more money, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there.
Speaker 1: make you know if it all those tickets go to original sellers Then that's it.
Speaker 1: Ticketmaster's revenue maxes out at full arena and also they make less money if the show doesn't sell out.
Speaker 0: So the only way to incentivize Ticketmaster to care at all about the negative impact of resellers In any capacity would be to make it illegal for them to get a second dip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could do that.
Speaker 0: the company that say would know they would still be happy though because they would or make anybody from Resells.
Speaker 1: they would still be happy for the resellers to guarantee that all the tickets get sold and to remove their risk.
Speaker 1: true So that it wouldn't be removing the second dip would would not really alleviate the situation.
Speaker 0: But that you could see.
Speaker 0: I could see Ticketmaster then tweaking their pricing With to try and sell make the initial fee higher.
Speaker 1: That's what I'll do.
Speaker 0: I mean really we should probably nationalize them too, but That's my answer to everything lately.
Speaker 1: You should be.
Speaker 1: only way is to make the actual ticket price correct so that there is no margin.
Speaker 0: We've said some sort of timed Dutch auction.
Speaker 0: The first ticket is a million dollars and it counts down.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly Anyway, so anyway got any news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's this animated movie from a long time ago, I've never seen it.
Speaker 1: I've never seen it.
Speaker 1: I think I've heard of it like one time and then forgot it.
Speaker 1: and it's like this vaguely familiar thing.
Speaker 1: It's like if you asked me about it, I would have thought like is that real?
Speaker 1: or is that Shazam?
Speaker 1: Kazaam whatever right what the Shaq one was real the Sinbad one wasn't.
Speaker 1: yep, regardless It's a movie Directed by Renee Lalou.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'm pronouncing your French name correctly.
Speaker 0: adapted from Stefan rules novel the orphan Undepended.
Speaker 1: Yeah But you know, the art was done by you know inspired by Mobius.
Speaker 1: right Mobius the comic artist Yeah was involved right and so it's like a. it's not that long.
Speaker 1: It's like a 40-something minute animation, I think It's really stunning.
Speaker 1: and it's you know, if you like a scavengers rain for example, very similar right even though this is much older Because they scavengers rain is similar to this not the other way around.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the they're getting Janus films, which is a production place that basically Brings back old movies.
Speaker 1: That's sort of what they do.
Speaker 1: Usually criterion collection films will often be from Janus films.
Speaker 1: They are doing a 4k remaster of this.
Speaker 1: that's gonna be Screened in New York City on July 26.
Speaker 1: So like in like a week and change and then I think it will be screened elsewhere.
Speaker 1: I imagine you'll avail eventually be able to just pay to watch it or get a beret if they still make those.
Speaker 1: but it's definitely something to be aware of because not easy to see.
Speaker 1: and 4k remaster.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna look better than it ever has.
Speaker 1: they recently did.
Speaker 1: Janus films Also did 4k remaster of Seven Samurai which was in the theater.
Speaker 1: I've seen it enough times.
Speaker 1: I didn't have time to go to the theater to see it again But hopefully I can do that on my 4k television at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I got a news that I learned about from Scott's news because the time masters receiving its 4k release.
Speaker 0: There's a breaking headline on the page.
Speaker 0: You linked me to at the top And I'm just gonna read the headline Centaur world creator Megan Nicole doing a direct bad fairies feature for Warner Brothers and locksmith animation.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I'm a fan of centaur world.
Speaker 0: It's uh, it's something.
Speaker 0: it's a musical I like.
Speaker 0: I like almost everything about it.
Speaker 0: I'm a sucker for musicals.
Speaker 0: I always have been the dumber the musical the more I'm into it.
Speaker 0: Like that's my mantra when it comes to musicals.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot going on with this.
Speaker 0: this movie is coming out in.
Speaker 1: That's a long ways off.
Speaker 0: it is a long ways off.
Speaker 0: It's part of locksmith animations.
Speaker 0: first look deal with Warner Brothers, which apparently is a whole thing.
Speaker 0: so there's this whole ideal that happened and this is one of the first things that's coming out of that deal, but Dneg animation is producing it and they are the same people who made Nimona
Speaker 1: mm-hmm
Speaker 0: and Apparently what this is about is quote Bad fairies is a subversive musical comedy set in a contemporary London about a badass gang of fairies.
Speaker 0: I Can't think of something that would speak to me more unless it was also involving dragons in some way like this feels so up my Alley, I'm gonna see this movie in 2027 probably not opening night because I don't see anything at opening night anymore, but I'll see this movie.
Speaker 0: I'm down.
Speaker 0: center world sold me.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot going on here that I learned about just now.
Speaker 0: that is apparently breaking news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if by the way, this is there's a website cartoon brew and that's where I get a lot of animation industry news.
Speaker 1: It's like it's a. it's a industry focused news site.
Speaker 1: So it's you know animators are reading this yeah and people in the film industry but it's just a website you can read and not like a trade publication you have to pay for.
Speaker 0: like the difference the article about this unlike Kotaku or something.
Speaker 0: we'll talk a lot about the fan perspective But this article is mostly about here's who's making it and here's where it came from And here's the names of people who are associated with the project.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you care about animation Industry especially in the US but also elsewhere You should read the news on that site and then you won't need to listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: And then I guess the third news we got.
Speaker 0: you sent me this this was uploaded 12 hours ago You may remember a couple years ago.
Speaker 0: There was out of kind of out of nowhere in Urusayetsura Anime reboot.
Speaker 0: they kind of just made that anime again, but with modern production Quality and it's pretty great.
Speaker 0: And apparently it's doing really well.
Speaker 0: It's already got two seasons.
Speaker 0: The last season just ended like a few weeks ago.
Speaker 1: I don't like what the ratings are, but I guess if they make in two seasons, someone's watching it.
Speaker 0: I watched a little bit of it and it's great but it's I mean it's there say it's sort of like I Read most of that manga and I watched the like most of the original anime.
Speaker 1: I read a whole volume of it and watch some episodes and a movie.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I think it's that they're doing that This is gonna happen to every old good thing or at least every Rumiko Takahashi thing because now Ranma 1/2 is getting the exact same treatment.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean there was already Sailor Moon Crystal Yeah, and then there's the Rose of Versailles movie.
Speaker 1: that's coming.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like.
Speaker 1: I think anime is finally gone to the.
Speaker 1: you know, they dud they did sequels they did prequels they did spin-offs.
Speaker 1: right and You know just like in the US where if you look at the list of upcoming movies Almost everything is a sequel adaptation spin-off whatever.
Speaker 1: right anime is now going into the HD remake territory Full on I mean what.
Speaker 1: there was a little bit of it already, but now even more so.
Speaker 0: so call me when Escaflowne gets its remake.
Speaker 0: That's the one I'd be watching for and I don't think that's in anyone's radar or pipe.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's gonna be those ones.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna be sticking to the.
Speaker 1: you know, the Big one.
Speaker 1: Yes, right something that was you know Dragon Ball level One piece.
Speaker 1: they could they could I could see them like Reanimating older one piece or Pokemon again, right?
Speaker 0: I mean if I like that if you wanted to speak to me the two I would want this treatment for would be Escaflowne and Irresponsible Captain Tyler or maybe Utena.
Speaker 0: But also I'm a weirdo and then I don't think the industry is gonna make any money off of any of those three ideas.
Speaker 1: No, but you know, it's a. it's a good way to Not have to do material, you know.
Speaker 1: Change things up and make anyone upset.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can really all you gotta do is be faithful to the original Because the Yurisa Yatsuro one was faithful to the original.
Speaker 1: Yeah from a making money perspective you get the old fans can enjoy it again in HD And maybe you'll get some new fans and keep your intellectual Because we've known for a long time and this comes up.
Speaker 0: It came up a lot even back when we were doing anime conventions.
Speaker 0: Lot of younger anime fans will not watch anything that looks old.
Speaker 0: They just won't like at all.
Speaker 0: They won't watch old movies.
Speaker 0: They won't watch old anime if it looks old.
Speaker 0: They just don't.
Speaker 0: they automatically bounce off of it.
Speaker 1: Mmm, it's just people that are better weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean I look I see something that looks new and I'm like that probably sucks It's too new.
Speaker 0: I was talking to a co-worker actually a couple weeks ago and he was complaining about how his kids Will not watch black and white movies like they think it's crazy to watch anything that's in black and white because that is ancient.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah All right, let's not we won't go to any museum then and look at a painting which They're much older than those black and white movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at least those paintings are in color.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so The YouTube shorts, I guess not really genre, but the format is hit or miss.
Speaker 0: But there are a very small number of people who have been making content in that Format and actually putting it on YouTube that are doing a pretty good job.
Speaker 0: and this channel Actually seems to be doing a pretty good job.
Speaker 0: and this video I'm linking to is titled ditching school and it is a 29 second animated song about a child who is skipping school and his mother who is Attempting to catch him in this and I laugh I laughed out loud.
Speaker 0: I thought it was really cute Yeah, but what's interesting about it?
Speaker 0: They made a version of it and then they made basically a better version of the same thing and they uploaded both of them.
Speaker 1: No, maybe it's like the pre animation and then the full yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, they're almost completely different like it's like an almost a different concept.
Speaker 1: Okay Maybe they're just redoing the same theme over and over.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sort of like, you know, well animation.
Speaker 0: I mean it's even titled like.
Speaker 0: they call it an animation meme and that's been a YouTube is lately as I've found these circles.
Speaker 0: There are tons of like little circles of Animators who will?
Speaker 0: someone will make a short animation and then like 50 people will make another animation.
Speaker 0: That's basically the same but with their own characters or their own style or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's cool.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: I like this trend.
Speaker 1: Alright, so Tim Eldred is a is it always, you know being a big-time person in the you know English-speaking anime scene, you know been an artist illustrator Animator on various, you know things such as like, you know, the star blazers comic that came out in the u.s Right, you know.
Speaker 1: and Tim Eldred's favorite mecha anime ever is photons, right and I was talking about vote times with some people on the internet a little while ago and there were some photons related questions and I did a search and the search result came up to Tim Eldred's page.
Speaker 1: I'm like, well if it's Tim Eldred's page, this must be a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Absolutely legit total, you know Trustworthy.
Speaker 1: everything here is correct every right.
Speaker 1: These are the right answers relating to vote Toms but what I didn't realize is that a Tom and on Tim Eldred's official website He is maintaining a armored trooper.
Speaker 1: vote Toms hub which is like basically like an old fan site with all kinds of materials and scans and photos and Information.
Speaker 0: this kind of website is 90% of the kinds of websites I would visit when I was in late middle school on the internet about all things vote Toms And he has updated the site as recently as July 1st 2024.
Speaker 1: He's like still this guy.
Speaker 1: it says right here like updated July 1st 2024 posted June 17th.
Speaker 1: So it's actually is.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's a new page that was posted on June 17th and updated July 1st But regardless the page is here and My god, is it?
Speaker 1: it's like going through this page is like going to like a vote Toms Museum.
Speaker 1: The vote Toms scans of the manga in particular.
Speaker 1: There are two mangas actually.
Speaker 1: They were basically the anime came out.
Speaker 1: I learned all this from these pages, by the way The anime came out and then there were two mangas that were adapting from the anime.
Speaker 1: One of them was in sort of a kids mag, you know manga magazine and the other one was in a different manga magazine.
Speaker 1: So the mangas have different themes like, you know Toms and different art styles, but they were adapting from the anime Not the other way around.
Speaker 1: And the scans of those mangas are like stunning.
Speaker 1: They're like unbelievable.
Speaker 1: So and that's just part of what is on this page.
Speaker 1: He's also got like here the model kids here the art books Here's the videos and laser discs and the merch.
Speaker 1: it's like everything.
Speaker 1: all vote Toms.
Speaker 1: things are here Pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: So we'll save spoilers.
Speaker 0: Obviously.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll just talk about this first.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk a little bit about the ending and if you I mean you can kind of see where this movie is going from the beginning, but Mars Express was really fun and it is exactly what Wikipedia says.
Speaker 0: it is a French animated neo-noir Sci-fi fiction film.
Speaker 1: Yep So I found out about this because G kids who is responsible for basically taking all the best anime movies and putting them Distributing them in the US and other places.
Speaker 1: They also distribute non anime animation from other countries.
Speaker 1: I guess they do.
Speaker 1: you have any live-action?
Speaker 1: I guess sometimes rare mostly animation.
Speaker 1: But you know that if G kids bothers to distribute something that it must be good.
Speaker 1: So they're really sort of like, you know for my eyes like a curator, right?
Speaker 1: it's like if you see their logo before the movie guaranteed good movie and They were distributing something called Mars Express the French animated neo-noir sci-fi movie And it was available You can.
Speaker 1: the way you can watch it legally is to pay the rental fee on any digital service of your choice YouTube's Amazon's Apple whatever right Whatever you like, it's not any of the streaming ones and I think it was like six dollars at least in the United States.
Speaker 1: Wait to watch it one time.
Speaker 1: I guess you can pay more if you want to just watch it infinitely And you can just watch it.
Speaker 1: No problem in French with English subtitles.
Speaker 1: And so I did.
Speaker 1: how could I how could I not go for?
Speaker 0: Something with that description and I guess what I would say is one.
Speaker 0: it was I loved it It was phenomenal, but it wasn't necessarily Original in the sense that no it was.
Speaker 0: basically take some of the best parts of Who's who of famous great science fiction film films and put them all in the same movie?
Speaker 1: That's pretty much what it was.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it wasn't like, you know, usually when someone says ah It's a mash-up of this and that two things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right a video game will be like, okay We're gonna take vampire survivors, but mix it with a shmup instead - there's a to combo.
Speaker 1: Right Mars Express is like a 10 combo you got.
Speaker 1: you got aspects of your 2001 Space Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Oh, we got Robocop like direct.
Speaker 1: got your Robocop and you got your Terminator and up, right?
Speaker 1: You got your alien.
Speaker 1: You got your fucking.
Speaker 1: of course your blade runners Tons of Blade Runner, there are some scenes that are almost cribbed from Ghost in the Shell and Terminator - Yeah, you got your ghost in the shells.
Speaker 1: You got your eye robots.
Speaker 1: You got fucking basically everything.
Speaker 0: Yep There's a lot of murder Murder bot type things happen.
Speaker 1: There's the surrogates which you know, not as big as the other examples for the surrogates.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like there is so much every thing from every sci-fi.
Speaker 1: Yeah is all in here right?
Speaker 0: ambiguity of a total recall.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the thing about this movie is that it is not like the greatest deepest movie of all time.
Speaker 0: Like we're gonna give this movie a lot of praise But this isn't like a movie that scholars are gonna freak out about but it is actually.
Speaker 1: it's really straightforward, right?
Speaker 1: It's like even though it has a lot of messaging.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know in the subtext.
Speaker 1: It's in the.
Speaker 1: it's in the text text.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why is he got those flowers?
Speaker 0: He pulls up to a house.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh, it's a robo cop.
Speaker 0: Oh And then it was a robo cop and then like, oh the update didn't work.
Speaker 0: And I was like.
Speaker 0: I pointed at the screen and said that's gonna be the plot.
Speaker 0: They didn't work on him.
Speaker 1: Of course Chekhov's update.
Speaker 0: Yep But this movie is executed so well and the fact that it can do such direct Homage and reference without Requiring any knowledge of all the things that's referencing.
Speaker 1: if you have if someone hasn't seen a whole bunch of sci-fi Movies and read a bunch of sci-fi novels like we have and just watches this out of nowhere They're gonna be like, oh my god.
Speaker 0: This is If I hadn't seen all the movies we just listed and I saw this out of nowhere it would have blown my goddamn mind.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So this movie is also like it's.
Speaker 0: it's French and I highly recommend you watch it in French as we did.
Speaker 0: We watched a little bit of the ball in English just to see.
Speaker 0: sorry French people, but the dubs fine but the French voice acting Sounds very good and very heartfelt and I and I feel like it is a very French film.
Speaker 0: like it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm always gonna watch anything in the original language Even if the there if even if it's true that like another country's voice actors did a better job Even cowboy bebop as much as I love that dub like the original voice acting is phenomenal in cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So Mars Express for being very straightforward.
Speaker 0: The thing that I like about it the most is that it really trusts the audience to pick up on stuff.
Speaker 0: It doesn't linger over points.
Speaker 0: It doesn't like over explain things.
Speaker 0: characters figure stuff out and take actions without anyone in the movie saying what they figured out.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's definitely not one of the movies where you're angry at the characters for being dum-dums.
Speaker 0: Nobody I would say no character does anything particularly stupid either.
Speaker 0: No, even the bad guys gonna get everyone they'll.
Speaker 0: everyone acts really reasonably According to their own motives.
Speaker 1: of course Some people have a bad motive and they work towards it, but they don't work towards it in a foolish manner.
Speaker 0: But knowing what they know, it's not a stupid movie plot thing of.
Speaker 0: why did that?
Speaker 0: Why did that character do that thing?
Speaker 0: That was stupid.
Speaker 0: It's ruined the movie for me, right?
Speaker 1: I mean the.
Speaker 1: the.
Speaker 1: the common thing of characters doing things that aren't smart or you know out of character or Foolish makes even less sense in a world with such high Technology right where they would have information and capabilities to do something better.
Speaker 0: So Blade Runner is the one I didn't mention.
Speaker 0: that is also said blade.
Speaker 1: I said blade run.
Speaker 0: I must not heard you say it because Blade Runner is relevant About every five or six minutes for the entire movie.
Speaker 0: Blade Runner is relevant and both both Blade Runners Yep, and then right at the end when you think okay, I think I know where this is going.
Speaker 0: There's one final set of plot beats and then Blade Runner is suddenly back in the forefront again Yep, and so are the culture books at that point.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So a plot summary, yeah, right there is a woman who is a detective But she is not a police detective.
Speaker 1: She works for basically a corporation.
Speaker 1: Yeah investigating and Basically, the the rule is is that robots have to have governors on them?
Speaker 1: like I robot right where they cannot break the robot law because the governor prevents that from happening.
Speaker 1: and And there are some people who are de-governing robots or people with robot bodies or other sorts of automata's.
Speaker 1: and She starts the movie trying to stop one such person and perhaps get a bounty on them by bringing them back to Mars - and It you know you get some.
Speaker 1: and she has a buddy cuz a buddy cop movie and her buddy is Indeed a robot who has the governor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but is not a robot in the sense of like a pure robot, but he's basically He's a.
Speaker 0: he's a robo cop situation except basically anyone who dies.
Speaker 0: if they have a backup They put the back up into a robot and they bring him back to life as a robot.
Speaker 0: So it's robo cop but on purpose by the person, right?
Speaker 1: Her partner is a dead person who their body died and their brain was uploaded into a robot body.
Speaker 1: And so like it's a robot but the head is a hologram of the formerly existing human body but it basically is that guy.
Speaker 1: in terms of personality Humanity his character design is great.
Speaker 1: Yeah is I think he's the best character.
Speaker 1: maybe It's the most the most fun character Even though he's got some dark Barrel the the the first supercomputer we meet.
Speaker 0: the non-biological one is a good character, even though he only saw her little.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah Oh, yeah, that's a good one, too.
Speaker 1: But yeah gets entangled and you know finds out that her old college buddies slash boss slash Corporate CEO guy is maybe up to no good.
Speaker 0: now This guy I gotta point out has such a robo cop villain name Chris Roy Jacker like.
Speaker 0: that's Bob.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's like.
Speaker 0: and the fact that her name her name is Roberta Williams the hacker.
Speaker 1: He's more like the Terminator 2 CEO guy because he's got a you know Or like, you know, he's got a mecha tank.
Speaker 1: that like he's trying to sell to the military and that it defends his house.
Speaker 1: That's definitely Terminator 2 slash Ghost in the Shell movie situation.
Speaker 0: But that tank is also a little bit of like Ghost in the Shell tank or the Tachikoma.
Speaker 1: That's what I said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 1: Does that you know?
Speaker 1: the one tank or turn made or two?
Speaker 1: There's the the one mecha.
Speaker 1: there was a robo cop.
Speaker 1: They're trying to sell the mecha.
Speaker 0: That was robo cop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the.
Speaker 1: yeah the mega not terminator Robocopra is trying to sell the.
Speaker 1: the CEO is trying to sell the robot.
Speaker 1: Yeah to the to the military
Speaker 0: And basically the plot is one of those like detective looking into a regular crime Finds a thread that they're gently advised by powerful people not to tug on and this character is very much portrayed as the kind of person who will not give up on anything ever and is super intense and invested and
Speaker 1: believes in justice Yep,
Speaker 0: and just won't give up and then follows the thread all the way to the end
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The other thing the character believes in that is sort of the central driving.
Speaker 1: I guess you know Whatever but is it's a very x-men thing where it's all about robot rights going on here, right?
Speaker 0: That's the central conflict of the the setting very very because we just watched Pluto the anime recently and now watching this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, same same thing Right, is that you know the robots, you know have these governors and they don't have a lot of rights.
Speaker 1: They're basically servants, you know subservient to the humans.
Speaker 1: But as they're portrayed in the world, they're completely human, right?
Speaker 1: It's just they're powerful because they have robot bodies and robot brains so they can win over humans And so that's why humans insist on them being governed.
Speaker 1: Also, there was some incident in the past where you know robots did a bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's that's what led to this and so that's sort of what the central conflict is is people who believe in robot rights and people who are like You know and they don't fuck around Blade Runner style.
Speaker 0: if a robots governor is off.
Speaker 0: that is like the most serious crime Yeah, but at the same time destroy it.
Speaker 0: We meet a robot early on who doesn't have a governor and he's hilarious and great and there's a great line where the hacker girl is talking to someone and she says something to the effect of.
Speaker 0: People are so afraid of jailbroken robots, but 90% of them just want to get stoned and play video games Like they don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna hurt anybody.
Speaker 1: Yep, again, that's also a murder bot situation.
Speaker 1: robots with governors.
Speaker 1: Yeah The animation is.
Speaker 0: it's not really like studying Are in the sense that one thing I noticed the characters make very subtle Facial expressions that I don't see in a lot of other animation like those subtle mouth movements are all over the place in this thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's a. it's a CG situation But it's not a 3d CG.
Speaker 1: I mean it probably is but it looks 2d when you're watching it.
Speaker 1: Yep And it's also looks like a French comic book, obviously.
Speaker 0: Yeah Hello looks like a French comic book.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like pick a random person on earth who's ever seen the internet and show this to them and they'll say is that a French Comic book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might have been who knows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you said it was a novel.
Speaker 1: it was based on.
Speaker 0: Uh, I said that about our other news a while back.
Speaker 0: I don't know what this was based on.
Speaker 1: Okay, good question.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I think at this point we can like the movie's great.
Speaker 0: I think everyone should see it Like.
Speaker 0: if you like sci-fi at all There's no reason not to watch this.
Speaker 0: and if you don't wreck if you haven't seen any of the movies we mentioned along the way You should watch all of those two without exception every one of them.
Speaker 1: Things only.
Speaker 1: this thing is only 90 minutes.
Speaker 1: All right, so it's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: there's a. whatever you're gonna do with 90 minutes today is Way more a waste of time than watching this movie.
Speaker 0: It is jam-packed.
Speaker 0: It never slows down It never drags.
Speaker 0: every time you think you see where it's going.
Speaker 0: it kind of ups the stakes a little bit and it also I like how it portrayed has a huge amount of environmental and background storytelling and world-building in that the mechanical details.
Speaker 0: the subtle like the seeing the society working is a huge part of this movie like the way crosswalks work and the way people work and the way apartment buildings are and like the way Offices look just like how Robocop and all these movies we reference portray a very particular kind of society.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this doesn't appear to be an adaptation of anything.
Speaker 1: It is a completely original work Unrelated to anything.
Speaker 1: not a sequel not a prequel not a remake not a nothing.
Speaker 1: So that's also a great reason to go out and Show that hey Hollywood Industry of art you should make things that are original more often even if they are not really original because it's an amalgamation of everything good ever.
Speaker 1: But I'll take an amalgamation of everything good ever.
Speaker 1: That's a new work then You know a remake of any one of those things.
Speaker 0: so we won't do like a full full Like grew lit create final thoughts.
Speaker 0: But from this point on I will say we're gonna spoil this movie because there are also.
Speaker 1: you saw it You saw it recently.
Speaker 1: I saw it like some weeks ago Just saw it.
Speaker 0: So a lot of things are very fresh in my mind.
Speaker 0: So from this point on spoilers and you should go watch this movie.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress that enough.
Speaker 0: But anyway It is very noteworthy that at the end very specifically you do not know if These robots are going off to colonize space or if they were all just murdered.
Speaker 0: yep, and I think that is very important because of the fact that We know of one robot the guy Robocop.
Speaker 0: He is not hacked by whatever the thing is, but he is.
Speaker 1: I don't have to he didn't have to go and Basically at the end all the robots go and upload themselves On spaceships right because they couldn't physically all fit on the spaceship.
Speaker 1: Yeah But they all go to this big.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of spaceships waiting for them.
Speaker 1: the update that tack their brains Basically forces them to go to the spaceships Upload their brains onto the spaceships and then the spaceships go off into space Supposedly to colonize elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that one guy whose brain was he didn't get the update.
Speaker 1: He didn't have to go upload himself and He does so anyway, yep He looked at the world around himself and he made that decision perfectly consciously and with those spaceships might have just gone and exploded somewhere.
Speaker 1: But it's like would they really go through all the effort of doing this - it's like if they hacked all the robots.
Speaker 1: They could have hacked them all to self-destruct.
Speaker 0: That's where this.
Speaker 0: the storytelling is subtle But the fact that it plays out and you get all these details But the movie doesn't like linger on them or try to explain them or over explain them.
Speaker 0: It's not clear who really actually did the hack because Roy Jacker Freaks out about how he's like, I'm just a pawn.
Speaker 0: I'm just a puppet like I'm doing this for them and it's implied Something bigger going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it might have out like it feels like a robot did this.
Speaker 0: and it's also not clear What the governor what the heck actually did.
Speaker 0: did it compel them to go the space or did it just remove the governor and give?
Speaker 0: them information?
Speaker 0: Maybe and we don't know could like total recall.
Speaker 1: You don't know what happened, but they did upload themselves and the spaceships did take off.
Speaker 1: So someone spent the money on a whole bunch of spaceships.
Speaker 1: Yeah that act and this, you know made this actually happen.
Speaker 0: but what I was impressed by is that you know our TR.
Speaker 0: if what we who a lot of people would perceive to the main character dies and then the movie keeps going for a while and That was one.
Speaker 0: I think that was a good Moderately shocking way to show who this story is really about because the story is about the robots.
Speaker 0: The story is about what a robots do and the humans are almost like the side characters because the robots are oppressed They're enslaved.
Speaker 1: She's basically if you think about it, the movie is you know, the main character.
Speaker 1: What's her name?
Speaker 1: Aline, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: She's sort of going around Giving you like a tour of the robot situation all around and she's an ally like she's all on board with her friends the robots.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she shows you her partner the robot and she shows you you know, she investigates robot situations.
Speaker 1: Right the people trying to ungovern robots You know, there's the the thing that gets it all kicked off.
Speaker 1: the girl who you know is doing is is basically selling out her Brain time.
Speaker 0: Yeah the subtle but important Undercurrent of Prostitution of a physical body or a prostitution of a brain or the same thing like yeah She had an illegal clone of herself made.
Speaker 1: they basically copied her brain illegally.
Speaker 1: You're not supposed to do that.
Speaker 1: Well, you can't do it into a sex spot and then when that sex spot works She gets money.
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: but the sex spot wasn't just sexing There was also renting out brain time for processing which is a big part of the plot But what's very important about that is that it doesn't dwell on that too much But it is implied that it is a super super serious crime to activate your own backup while you're still alive Which leads to the question of why is that a crime that feels a lot like in?
Speaker 0: Modern world when conservatives ban things that are perfectly fine because they're weird about it.
Speaker 1: Yes, but also I get you know I can imagine like what if I just made a hundred knees then it would just be the whole world become a battle of who Can make the most of themselves,
Speaker 0: but the world has always been that for all of history who makes the most babies
Speaker 1: Part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's there was he making babies and just like I have a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: So I made a million scots.
Speaker 0: now you're fucked but rich people can definitely just buy as many robots as they want.
Speaker 0: Anyway Sure, but it's interesting that they specifically like it's applied that it's super rare.
Speaker 0: And also they're going after this girl like she committed mega felony when literally all she did is Turn on her backup to make some extra money to pay for college.
Speaker 0: She wasn't hurting anybody.
Speaker 1: well, she also the thing they're actually going after her for is because she She did some.
Speaker 1: she rents out her brain, but then she managed to avoid losing her memory and remember members Right.
Speaker 1: She remembers what they used her brain to do and then she used and she uses that knowledge right to basically You know make you know You know to hack a robot basically and repeat it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you know, the robot is the robot kills her or she killed.
Speaker 1: I forget Which.
Speaker 1: she kills her so I don't remember.
Speaker 1: but no the robot kills her right after she unlocks it.
Speaker 0: well So but it's remember the assassin comes to get her to make sure that she doesn't have this memory.
Speaker 1: Ah, yes Yes, correct.
Speaker 0: Cuz the robot that gets away basically just tries to run like just to get away.
Speaker 0: It's not trying to hurt anyone it freaks out and runs.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that's what they're actually going after.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not for the just.
Speaker 0: the other part implied that because the PI.
Speaker 0: she doesn't know about that and they still like she.
Speaker 0: the Official answer is they're going after her because it's a mega felony to turn on a backup if you're not dead.
Speaker 0: But obviously the real reason is because of this code because as we know when robots get jail broken They just get stoned and have sex like.
Speaker 0: that's 90% of what all robots do when they get.
Speaker 0: I like how it portrays robot sex Too.
Speaker 0: it's basically just information sharing Mm-hmm But at the end I do also appreciate the.
Speaker 0: that is when you know you just got you mentioned 2001 and at the end you get a very very very 2001 space baby style scene as Carlos uploads himself into basically the singularity and it is portrayed as both orgasmic and fractal.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Think this movie just has a lot to say.
Speaker 0: like we could you could easily do a very long lit crit conversation about it
Speaker 1: And it's kind of shocking that like any of the things that this borrows from are in them in and of themselves Very long and they managed to take all those things to do them all in 90 minutes
Speaker 0: And do them all justice.
Speaker 0: like this movie directly addresses the core science fiction questions and ethical questions of All the other movies we listed and again, they're all in the same movie.
Speaker 0: and I think what strikes me the most is that ultimately Regarding if the robots escapes if they did if this was them basically escaping enslavement so they can go be Whatever they are that is far beyond what humans are that humans are harming them or holding them back.
Speaker 0: Then it's also implied that The deaths that happen along the way were necessary and justified in that those like there's that you know, all this all the all the plants who vote at the end to Basically, let Roy Jacker die and kill anyone they need to kill to make sure that the plot succeeds.
Speaker 0: They decided that that was that that was the cause was more important than the lives of the few people who died along the way.
Speaker 0: And I think it's a very French story around How much death are and chaos are you willing to accept to achieve a just end or to fight against injustice?
Speaker 0: because that is a very impossible question for humans to answer authoritatively or convincingly mmm, and I think that's one of the core themes of this movie because The way humans treat robots in this movie is absolutely unethical.
Speaker 0: So then the question is how many humans is it acceptable to kill to end that situation?
Speaker 1: No Watch this movie.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Absolutely watch this movie.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion links and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays gaming and games.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 0: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 0: The nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 4.0 International license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Linky G to a blue teddy bear case chair makes music.
Speaker 0: Chris the dot Christopher Clinton Walton fin Joel Hayes penny rhymer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson sure about horrible in a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names Tonight.
Speaker 0: I leave you with something you should have seen coming.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a bop and I got weirdly stuck in my head.
Speaker 0: But anyway, why aren't you at school?
Speaker 0: I am your school.
Speaker 0: Just called me.
Speaker 0: They said you're not there.
Speaker 0: That's not true.
Speaker 0: Stop lying, mom.
Speaker 0: I promise you You're grounded for six months.
Speaker 0: want to keep lying.
Speaker 0: I didn't ditch school.
Speaker 0: if you don't believe me come see for yourself.
Speaker 1: Fine I will.
Speaker 1: you're coming to my school driving to your school now.